http://www.tacomacc.edu/about/policies/privacy-policy

Skip to the content
Welcome to Fall Quarter!
Covid-19: TCC’s Safe Start practices. Get Virtual Help. Information for Current Students.
Connect with us and read more
Close
Policies
HomeA to Z IndexSitemapAboutToggle Sub MenuWhy TCC?NewsroomPoliciesLeadershipAccreditationCampusesThe TCC FoundationEmploymentOur Mission and VisionEmployment2018 Annual ReportTCC Distinguished AlumniAcademics & ProgramsToggle Sub MenuProgramsContinuing EducationBasic Education, ESL & GED®College + High SchoolAcademic Support & ResourcesThe Washington 45StatwayHonors ProgramHealth Careers Distinction PathwaysBusiness & Accounting Programs College CatalogAcademic CalendarLearning CommunitiesCosts & AdmissionToggle Sub MenuThe Admission ProcessInternational StudentsTuition & PaymentFinancial AidScholarships & Funding ProgramsRequest InfoTranscript RequestVisit CampusEnrollment VerificationTCC LifeToggle Sub MenuEventsAround CampusOur StoriesArts & CultureOffice of Student EngagementCampus ServicesAthleticsSafe ZoneCareer CenterCounselingLife Support and ResourcesLife ResourcesBlack Lives Matter at TCCHow Can We Help You?Toggle Sub MenuI want to transfer to a four-year collegeI want to earn college credit while in high schoolI'm a VeteranstafffacultymemberI Want to Donate to TCCI want to attend college for first timeI Want to Earn a High School DiplomaI'm a Current StudentI help people who want to attend college I'm interested in professional development for my business.I want a professional-technical certificate and/or degreeHigh School - CollegeHigh School + College Credit at TCCClass of 2019 Outstanding StudentsCoronavirus Disease-2019 (COVID-19): TCC InformationTCC Virtual HelpHealth CheckFall Quarter 2020 LearningFlexible FallFlexible FallToggle Sub MenuFlexible Fall: High School Seniors and ParentsCovid-19 InformationToggle Sub MenuFall 2020 Plan (Phase 2)
Home
About
Policies
Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy
Introduction
Thank you for visiting the Tacoma Community College website and reviewing our Privacy
Notice. This statement addresses collection, use, and security of and access to information
that may be obtained through use of Tacoma Community College Web site. This notice
covers the following topics:
Information collected if you only browse this site.If you do nothing during your visit to our website but browse, read pages, or download
information, we will gather and store certain information about your visit. This information
does not identify you personally. We automatically collect and store the following
information about your visit:
The Internet Protocol Address and domain name used. The Internet Protocol address
is a numerical identifier assigned either to your Internet service provider or directly
to your computer. We use the Internet Protocol Address to direct Internet traffic
to you. This address can be translated to determine the domain name of your service
provider (for example, xcompany.com or yourschool.edu);
The type of browser and operating system you used;
The date and time you visited this site;
The web pages or services you accessed at this site; and
The website you visited prior to coming to this website.
The information we automatically collect or store is logged and used by Tacoma Community
College only to improve the content of our web services and to help us understand
how people are using our services. Tacoma Community College analyzes the website logs
to determine how our website is being used, so that we may continually improve the
site's usefulness to the public.
What we collect if you volunteer information.If during your visit to our website you participate in a survey, send an email, or
perform some other transaction online, the following additional information will be
collected:
The email address, and contents of email, for those who communicate with us via email.
Information volunteered in response to a survey.
Information volunteered through an on-line form for any other purpose.
The information collected is not limited to text characters and may include audio,
video, and graphic information formats you send us.
We use your email to respond appropriately. This may be to respond to you, to address
issues you may identify, to further improve our website, or to forward the email to
another agency for appropriate action.
Personal Information and Choice
You may choose whether to provide personal information online.
Personal information is information about a natural person that is readily identifiable
to that specific individual. Personal information includes such things as an individual's
name, address, and phone number. A domain name or Internet Protocol address is not
considered personal information.
We collect no personal information about you unless you voluntarily provide it to
us by sending us email, participating in a survey, or completing an online form. You
may choose not to contact us by email, participate in a survey or to provide any personal
information using an online form. Your choice to not participate in these activities
will not impair your ability to browse the Tacoma Community College website and read
or download any information provided on the site. Alternative methods to online forms
and emailed requests for information are available. You can contact Tacoma Community
College by mail, fax, telephone or in person.
If personal information is requested on the website or volunteered by the user, state
law and the federal Privacy Act of 1974 may protect it. However, this information
is a public record once you provide it, and may be subject to public inspection and
copying if not protected by federal or state law.
If you believe that your personal information is being used for a purpose other than
what was intended when submitted, you may contact the Public Records Officer as shown in the Contact Information section of this statement.
The Tacoma Community College web site is a general audience site and we do not knowingly
collect any personal information from children. Users are cautioned that the collection
of personal information requested from or volunteered by children online or by email
will be treated the same as information given by an adult, and may be subject to public
access.
Public Access to Information
In the State Of Washington, laws exist to ensure that government is open and that
the public has a right to access appropriate records and information possessed by
state government. At the same time, there are exceptions to the public's right to
access public records that serve various needs including the privacy of individuals.
Exceptions are provided by both state and federal laws.
All of the information collected at this site becomes public records that may be subject
to inspection and copying by members of the public, unless an exemption in law exists.
Statute RCW 42.17. 260(1) states that:
Each agency, in accordance with published rules, shall make available for public inspection
and copying all public records, unless the record falls within the specific exemptions
of subsection (6) of this section [RCW 42.17.260(6)], RCW 42.17.310, 42.17.315, or
other statute which exempts or prohibits disclosure of specific information or records.
To the extent required to prevent an unreasonable invasion of personal privacy interests
protected by RCW 42.17.310 and 42.17.315, an agency shall delete identifying details
in a manner consistent with RCW 42.17.310 and 42.17.315 when it makes available or
publishes any public record; however, in each case, the justification for the deletion
shall be explained fully in writing.
In the event of a conflict between this Privacy Notice and the Public Records Act
or other law governing the agency's disclosure of records, the Public Records Act
or other applicable law will control.
Nondisclosure of Certain Personal Information
You may be required to provide certain personal information when you use the web-enabled
applications that are described below.
Credit Card Payment
Tacoma Community College may require you to provide certain personal information in
order to pay tuition and fees over the Web. The information is required in order to
verify your identify and to verify your credit card number and expiration date. You
may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we
will be unable to apply tuition and fee payment over the Web, and you will have to
pay your tuition and fees in person or by mail.
The following laws and regulations may prevent Tacoma Community College from disclosing
the personal information about you except for directory information. Only directory
information can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a
release in order to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information.
Education information may be released to other institutions that have requested the
records and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released
to a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if
information is requested officially by means of a subpoena, court order or legal report.
Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters
if officially requested. Tacoma Community College policy defines directory information
as student name, degrees and awards received. The College may also confirm dates of
attendance, date of birth, major field of study, participation in officially recognized
sports and activities and the most recent previous educational institution attended.
Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA)Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g)
otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
RCW 42.17.310 (a) and (ss) exempts the following from public inspection and copying: (a) Personal
information in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients or clients
of public institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients; (ss) Credit
card numbers, debit card numbers, electronic check numbers, card expiration dates,
or bank or other financial account numbers supplied to an agency for the purpose of
electronic transfer of funds, except when disclosure is expressly required by law.
Degree Audit
Tacoma Community College may require you to provide certain personal information in
order to perform a degree audit of your records over the Web. The information is required
in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information,
but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to display a degree audit of
your records over the Web, and you will have to request a degree audit in person.
The following laws and regulations may prevent Tacoma Community College from disclosing
the personal information about you except for directory information. Only directory
information can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a
release in order to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information.
Education information may be released to other institutions that have requested the
records and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released
to a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if
information is requested officially by means of a subpoena, court order or legal report.
Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters
if officially requested. Tacoma Community College policy defines directory information
as student name, degrees and awards received. The College may also confirm dates of
attendance, date of birth, major field of study, participation in officially recognized
sports and activities and the most recent previous educational institution attended.
Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA)Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g)
otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
RCW 42.17.310 exempts the following from public inspection and copying: (a) Personal information
in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients or clients of public
institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.
Financial Aid Inquiry
Tacoma Community College may require you to provide certain personal information in
order to obtain your financial aid status over the Web. The information is required
in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information,
but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to give you your financial aid
status over the Web, and you will have to obtain this information in person.
The following laws and regulations may prevent Tacoma Community College from disclosing
the personal information about you except for directory information. Only directory
information can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a
release in order to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information.
Education information may be released to other institutions that have requested the
records and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released
to a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if
information is requested officially by means of a subpoena, court order or legal report.
Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters
if officially requested. Tacoma Community College policy defines directory information
as student name, degrees and awards received. The College may also confirm dates of
attendance, date of birth, major field of study, participation in officially recognized
sports and activities and the most recent previous educational institution attended.
Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA)Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g)
otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
RCW 42.17.310 exempts the following from public inspection and copying: (a) Personal information
in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients or clients of public
institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.
Hope and Lifetime Learning Tax Credit
Tacoma Community College may require you to provide certain personal information in
order to allow you to view and copy course enrollment and payment information. The
information is required in order to provide you with the tax information needed for
compliance with the Internal Revenue Service reporting requirements for the Hope and
Lifetime Leaning tax credits. You may choose not to provide this information, but
if you choose not to provide it, we will be unable to display your enrollment and
payment information and you will have to obtain a copy of your enrollment and payment
records either in person or by mail.
The following laws and regulations may prevent Tacoma Community College from disclosing
the personal information about you except for directory information. Only directory
information can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a
release in order to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information.
Education information may be released to other institutions that have requested the
records and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released
to a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if
information is requested officially by means of a subpoena, court order or legal report.
Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters
if officially requested. Tacoma Community College policy defines directory information
as student name, degrees and awards received. The College may also confirm dates of
attendance, date of birth, major field of study, participation in officially recognized
sports and activities and the most recent previous educational institution attended.
Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA)Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g)
otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
RCW 42.17.310 exempts the following from public inspection and copying: (a) Personal information
in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients or clients or public
institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.
Registration
Tacoma Community College may require you to provide certain personal information in
order to register for classes over the Web. The information is required in order to
verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose
not to provide it you will be unable to register for classes over the Web, and you
will have to register for classes in person.
The following laws and regulations may prevent Tacoma Community College from disclosing
the personal information about you except for directory information. Only directory
information can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a
release in order to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information.
Education information may be released to other institutions that have requested the
records and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released
to a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if
information is requested officially by means of a subpoena, court order or legal report.
Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters
if officially requested. Tacoma Community College policy defines directory information
as student name, degrees and awards received. The College may also confirm dates of
attendance, date of birth, major field of study, participation in officially recognized
sports and activities and the most recent previous educational institution attended.
Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA)Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g)
otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
RCW 42.17.310 exempts the following from public inspection and copying: (a) Personal information
in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients or clients of public
institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.
Registration Appointment
Tacoma Community College may require you to provide certain personal information in
order to obtain your registration appointment information over the Web. The information
is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information,
but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to display your registration
appointment information over the Web, and you will have to obtain your registration
appointment information address in person.
The following laws and regulations may prevent Tacoma Community College from disclosing
the personal information about you except for directory information. Only directory
information can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a
release in order to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information.
Education information may be released to other institutions that have requested the
records and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released
to a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if
information is requested officially by means of a subpoena, court order or legal report.
Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters
if officially requested. Tacoma Community College policy defines directory information
as student name, degrees and awards received. The College may also confirm dates of
attendance, date of birth, major field of study, participation in officially recognized
sports and activities and the most recent previous educational institution attended.
Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA)Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g)
otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
RCW 42.17.310 exempts the following from public inspection and copying: (a) Personal information
in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients or clients of public
institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.
Schedule Planner
Tacoma Community College may require you to provide certain personal information in
order to check requisites while using schedule planner. The information is required
in order to access your academic and testing records. You may choose not to provide
this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to verify
your eligibility for enrollment into certain classes and you may be blocked from enrolling
into those classes.
The following laws and regulations may prevent Tacoma Community College from disclosing
the personal information about you except for directory information. Only directory
information can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a
release in order to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information.
Education information may be released to other institutions that have requested the
records and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released
to a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if
information is requested officially by means of a subpoena, court order or legal report.
Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters
if officially requested. Tacoma Community College policy defines directory information
as student name, degrees and awards received. The College may also confirm dates of
attendance, date of birth, major field of study, participation in officially recognized
sports and activities and the most recent previous educational institution attended.
Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA)Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g)
otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
RCW 42.17.310 exempts the following from public inspection and copying: (a) Personal information
in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients or clients of public
institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.
Student Address Change
Tacoma Community College may require you to provide certain personal information in
order to change your address over the Web. The information is required in order to
verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose
not to provide it we will be unable to change your address over the Web, and you will
have to change your address in person or by mail.
The following laws and regulations may prevent Tacoma Community College from disclosing
the personal information about you except for directory information. Only directory
information can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a
release in order to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information.
Education information may be released to other institutions that have requested the
records and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released
to a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if
information is requested officially by means of a subpoena, court order or legal report.
Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters
if officially requested. Tacoma Community College policy defines directory information
as student name, degrees and awards received. The College may also confirm dates of
attendance, date of birth, major field of study, participation in officially recognized
sports and activities and the most recent previous educational institution attended.
Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA)Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g)
otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
RCW 42.17.310 exempts the following from public inspection and copying: (a) Personal information
in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients or clients of public
institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.
Student PIN Change
Tacoma Community College may require you to provide certain personal information in
order to change your personal identification number over the Web. The information
is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information,
but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to change your PIN over the
Web, and you will have to change your PIN in person.
The following laws and regulations may prevent Tacoma Community College from disclosing
the personal information about you except for directory information. Only directory
information can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a
release in order to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information.
Education information may be released to other institutions that have requested the
records and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released
to a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if
information is requested officially by means of a subpoena, court order or legal report.
Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters
if officially requested. Tacoma Community College policy defines directory information
as student name, degrees and awards received. The College may also confirm dates of
attendance, date of birth, major field of study, participation in officially recognized
sports and activities and the most recent previous educational institution attended.
Student Schedule
Tacoma Community College may require you to provide certain personal information in
order to view your quarterly schedule. The information is required in order to verify
you identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not
to provide it we will be unable to display your quarterly schedule over the Web, and
you will have to obtain a copy of your quarterly schedule in person.
The following laws and regulations may prevent Tacoma Community College from disclosing
the personal information about you except for directory information. Only directory
information can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a
release in order to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information.
Education information may be released to other institutions that have requested the
records and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released
to a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if
information is requested officially by means of a subpoena, court order or legal report.
Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters
if officially requested. Tacoma Community College policy defines directory information
as student name, degrees and awards received. The College may also confirm dates of
attendance, date of birth, major field of study, participation in officially recognized
sports and activities and the most recent previous educational institution attended.
Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA)Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g)
otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
RCW 42.17.310 exempts the following from public inspection and copying: (a) Personal information
in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients or clients of public
institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.
Unofficial Transcript
Tacoma Community College may require you to provide certain personal information in
order to view your unofficial transcript over the Web. The information is required
in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information,
but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to display your unofficial transcript
over the Web, and you will have to view your unofficial transcript in person or by
mail.
The following laws and regulations may prevent Tacoma Community College from disclosing
the personal information about you except for directory information. Only directory
information can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a
release in order to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information.
Education information may be released to other institutions that have requested the
records and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released
to a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if
information is requested officially by means of a subpoena, court order or legal report.
Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters
if officially requested. Tacoma Community College policy defines directory information
as student name, degrees and awards received. The College may also confirm dates of
attendance, date of birth, major field of study, participation in officially recognized
sports and activities and the most recent previous educational institution attended.
Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA)Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g)
otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
RCW 42.17.310 exempts the following from public inspection and copying: (a) Personal information
in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients or clients of public
institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.
Review and Correction of Personally Identifiable Information
You can review any personally identifiable information Tacoma Community College collects
about you by using the information in the Contact Information section at the end of
this Notice. You may recommend changes to your personally identifiable information
you believe to be inaccurate by submitting a written request that credibly shows the
inaccuracy. We will take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting
access or making corrections (RCW 43.105.310).
Cookies
To better serve our users, we are now using "cookies" to customize your browsing experience
with the Tacoma Community College Web site. Cookies are simple text files stored on
your computer by your Web browser.
Cookies created on your computer by using this Web site do not contain personally
identifying information and do not compromise your privacy or security. We use the
cookie feature to store the following information on your computer:
Session login information
Limited personal information, such as name
Security
Tacoma Community College, as developer and manager of its website has taken several
steps to safeguard the integrity of its data and prevent unauthorized access to information
maintained by Tacoma Community College. These measures are designed and intended to
prevent corruption of data, block unknown or unauthorized access to our systems and
information, and to provide reasonable protection of private information in our possession.
This information should not be construed in any way as giving business, legal, or
other advice, or warranting as fail proof, the security of information provided via
Tacoma Community College websites.
Disclaimer
The Tacoma Community College website has many links to other websites. These include
links to websites operated by other government agencies, nonprofit organizations and
private businesses. When you link to another site, you are no longer on the Tacoma
Community College website and this Privacy Notice will not apply. When you link to
another website, you are subject to the privacy policy of that new site.
Neither the State of Washington, nor any agency, officer, or employee of the State
of Washington warrants the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of any information
published by this system, nor endorses any content, viewpoints, products, or services
linked from this system, and shall not be held liable for any losses caused by reliance
on the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of such information. Portions of such information
may be incorrect or not current. Any person or entity that relies on any information
obtained from this system does so at their own risk.
Tacoma Community College reserves the right to revise and update this Privacy Notice
at any time by posting such revised Privacy Notice at the Tacoma Community College
home page.
Tacoma Community College Contact Information
You may contact Tacoma Community College as follows:
To review your personal information, or request correction of your personal information:
RegistrarTacoma Community College6501 South 19th StreetTacoma, WA 98466253-566-5325 Phone253-566-6034 Faxenrollmentservices@tacomacc.edu
To offer comments about Tacoma Community College's Web site or about the information
presented in this Privacy Notice:
WebmasterTacoma Community College6501 South 19th StreetTacoma, WA 98466253.566.6051 Phone253.566.6387 Faxwebmaster@tacomacc.edu
©
